<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolios on Significant Game</title>
    <link>/portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Portfolios on Significant Game</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Injury Polar Plots</title>
      <link>/portfolio/injury-polar-plots/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/injury-polar-plots/</guid>
      <description>Injury data has been a bit of a guilty pleasure for me recently. When browsing through some of the data from Transfermarkt I looked into different ways of visualizing it. Specifically I was focused on highlighting injury lengths and their distribution over a player’s career.
Screenshot from transfermarkt.com
 This resulted in the below viz for Marco Reus which is inspired by how I view the (European) football calendar: running counter-clockwise and with the summer break at 6 o’clock.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Thomas Grønnemark changed Liverpools Throw-Ins</title>
      <link>/portfolio/how-thomas-gr%C3%B8nnemark-changed-liverpools-throw-ins/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/how-thomas-gr%C3%B8nnemark-changed-liverpools-throw-ins/</guid>
      <description>A lot has been written about Thomas Grønnemark’s appointment as Liverpool’s throw-in coach. In this post I will try to dig a little bit deeper and consult the numbers to see if I can seperate the myths from the facts and if I can unearth something that hasn’t been written before. I will start with summarizing what I have read so far. As probably many of you I haven’t given throw-ins much thought except for the occasional view on the time they take (mostly too long because my team is behind, the game is always over and the all the ball boys seem to have vanished).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lionel Messi - Free Kick Dashboard</title>
      <link>/portfolio/lionel-messi-free-kick-dashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/lionel-messi-free-kick-dashboard/</guid>
      <description>I finally had some time to play around with the free Statsbomb data. I previously wanted to look into using the crosstalk package to link interactive charts and this data set which includes all of Messi’s La Liga free kicks gave me a good excuse.
 Launch Dashboard  
The initial idea was to link the location of free kicks to their goal impact (or their impact outside of the goal as long as they are not blocked).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantifying Injury Rates</title>
      <link>/portfolio/quantifying-injury-rates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/quantifying-injury-rates/</guid>
      <description>Being a Bayern Munich supporter, injuries have been a big part of past campaigns. During most of the past season (2017/2018) Manuel Neuer was injured with a broken foot. For the second match against Real Madrid in the Champions League semi finals the team had to additionally compensate the injuries of Jérôme Boateng, Arturo Vidal, Kingsley Coman and Arjen Robben. While Pep Guardiola was still coach at Bayern his dispute with the long-serving team doctor Mueller-Wohlfahrt culminated into him resigning after 38 years with the team (Mueller-Wohlfahrt was later reinstated in 2017).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is possession data getting more extreme?</title>
      <link>/portfolio/is-possession-data-getting-more-extreme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/is-possession-data-getting-more-extreme/</guid>
      <description>The possession metric is probably one of the football statistics which is cited most often. It has gained even more media attention since we have seen larger divergence in possession across teams. Oversimplified game approaches of teams are often broadly categorized between possession-oriented and counter-attacking: think about Barcelona/Bayern Munich/Manchester City vs Chelsea/Borussia Dortmund/Liverpool.
At first glance the possession statistic seems to be fairly trivial: who controls most of the ball during the 90 minutes?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>